Zeeshan Khalid Flutter Developer

zeeshan.khalid21@yahoo.com

Islamabad

https://www.youtube.com/@codewithzee

03066077812

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/eshanz8

https://github.com/eshanz7?tab=repositories

Profile

A software engineer with strong development knowledge of Flutter app development, Rest API and Firebase with over 3 years of development experience (started as a native android developer).

Skills

Flutter

Getx, Provider, Bloc State Management , Unit Testing, Integration Testing

Version Control

Git on GitHub

Services

Firebase Authentication (OTP) - Firebase Notification (FCM) - Google Maps - Geolocator -Flutter Localizations.

Tools

Android Studio, Jira, Trello

Database

Firebase- Shared Preferences - SQLite - Hive

Architecture Pattern

MVC - MVVM - Repository

Progamming Languages

Dart - Java - Kotlin - Swift - Python

Other Skills

Clean Code - SOLID Principle - Debugging - Agile development - Clear understanding of OOP.

Professional Experience

2022/10 – present Islamabad, Pakistan

Flutter Developer

Uruk IT Solutions

- Developed two Flutter mobile applications from scratch (TFM Courier ☑ and TFM Shipper ☑), one for riders to mark pickups and shipments as delivered or non-delivered and scan shipments with barcode, and another for shippers to create pickups and shipments, track shipments, and view information on shipments and pickups collected.
- Implemented MVVM architecture and used dependency injection, Provider, and REST APIs to create modular, scalable, and efficient applications with clean code and best practices.
- Conducted integration testing on the shipper app using Flutter's testing framework to ensure app functionality and quality.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to gather requirements, design UI/UX, and implement features within project timelines and budget constraints.
- Managed projects using Agile methodologies, tracking progress and delivering high-quality software on time.

2021/05 – 2022/09 Islamabad, Pakistan

Flutter Developer

Solis Solutions

- Contributed to the development, bug fixing, testing, and maintenance of multiple social media apps (e.g., Dividis Tribe, Affinity) and NodeChain, a marketplace for buying and selling NFTs with Stripe payment integration and user wallet functionality.
- Implemented responsive design principles to ensure optimal user experience across multiple
- Localized apps by translating UI/UX into user interface code to support different languages and regions.

- Collaborated with the back-end team to integrate APIs and ensure seamless communication between front-end and back-end systems.
- Worked with Firebase to implement backend services such as notifications, remote config, and authentication features (email and phone) as well as the Firestore database.
- Utilized different state management packages like Provider and GetX to manage app state and data flow.
- Created and uploaded clones of the same apps to the Google Play Store and Apple Store, demonstrating a strong understanding of app publishing processes and procedures.

2020/09 – 2021/04 Islamabad, Pakistan

Android/Flutter Developer

JSOL Technologies

- Developed a Flutter app from scratch that integrated with Gmail and Microsoft APIs to fetch emails for user and show unread emails counts against each email in form of graphs such as pie charts and bar charts.
- I have read all the installed apps in user phones and user can select different apps from list so he can see which app has how many unread notifications in form of bar chart and pie chart
- Worked on an existing ecommerce-based Flutter app that connected with an admin panel in Laravel and used Firebase for notifications, bug fixing, and adding multi-language support.
- Developed multiple Native Android apps using Firebase and Firestore database as the backend.

Education

2015/10 - 2019/10

Bachelor's in Computer Engineering

University of Engineering & Technology Taxila [2]

Projects

E-CURE: HEALTH MONITORING ANDROID APP

- The purpose of our project is to develop a health monitoring application that will facilitate the users at home. It helps user to get any information about the doctor, diet and diseases.
- Three main features of app the are body mass index ,seasonal diseases precautions and treatment, interaction with doctor through messages and video call.
- Every patient according to the disease will see a list of doctors, then they can get the appointment from the doctor for consultation and the fee of the appointment will be paid by scanning the QR code.

Extract Frames Flutter App

- The purpose of project was record a 4K/ 60fps video of 60 seconds, exteracting its 300 frames, converting all into 300 images ,saving it in storage of phone by reducing the size and keeping the aspect ratio of 3820 x 2160 and finally upload it to google drive.
- I worked with camera plugin to record video with max resolution of device (4k) by allowing only back camera and stop the video automatically after 60 seconds, path provider plugin to get the path to stored in internal storage, gallery saver to saved images and modified extract flutter frames package to increase the speed of frames extraction.

Windmill General Trading LLC (Ecommerce app)

- Development of a fully ecommerce based mobile application for a client that has different features like sorting, filtration of products, bundle deals, cart, order placement using woo commerce backend.
- Integrated APIs using dio and Provider, Firestore Database, Firebase Authentication and Firebase Messaging also used.

Languages

• English

• Urdu

Certificates

• Introduction To Flutter Development (The App Brewery) □